<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2016 SkyzohKey <skyzohkey@framasphere.org> -->
<component type="desktop">
 <id>ricin.desktop</id>
 <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-3.0</metadata_license>
 <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
 <name>Ricin</name>
 <summary>Dead simple, privacy oriented, instant messaging app!</summary>
 <description>
  <p>
   Ricin aims to be a modern way to securely communicate with people that matter to you.
  </p>
  <p>
    Whether it's corporations or governments, digital surveillance today is widespread.
  </p>
  <p>
    Ricin Messenger is easy-to-use software that connects you with your friends and your
    family without anyone else listening in. While other big-name services require you
    to pay for features, Ricin Messenger is completely free and comes without advertising
     — forever. 
  </p>
  <p>Features:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Instant Messaging: Chat instantly across the globe with Ricin's secure messages.</li>
    <li>Voice: Keep in touch with friends and family using Ricin's completely free and encrypted voice calls.</li>
    <li>Video: Catch up face to face, over Ricin's secure video calls.</li>
    <li>Screen sharing: Stream your desktop with your friends with Ricin's secure screen sharing.</li>
    <li>File transfers: Trade files, with no artificial limits or caps and enhanced security.</li>
    <li>Group chats: Chat, call, and share video and files with the whole gang in Ricin's group chats.</li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    Ricin is developed with users privacy in mind, we wants you to be safe while chatting!
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>ENCRYPTED: Everything you do with Ricin Messenger is encrypted using open-source libraries. The only people who can see your conversations are the people you're talking with.</li>
    <li>DISTRIBUTED: Ricin has no central servers that can be raided, shut down, or forced to turn over data — the network is made up of its users. Say goodbye to server outages!</li>
    <li>FREE: Ricin is free software. That's free as in freedom, as well as in price. This means Ricin is yours — to use, modify, and share — because Ricin is developed by and for the users.</li>
  </ul>
 </description>
 <screenshots>
  <screenshot type="default">
   <image>https://cdn.ricin.im/images/ricin_01.png</image>
   <caption>A redacted screen of an ongoing conversation on Ricin.</caption>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
   <image>https://cdn.ricin.im/images/ricin_02.png</image>
   <caption>A redacted screen of an ongoing conversation on Ricin, using the clear theme.</caption>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
    <image>https://framasphere.org/camo/a4916d8a8b87174a1f4e073490a4d684348d88df/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f617046756b32442e706e67</image>
    <caption>A screenshot of Ricin with The Tox Theme.</caption>
 </screenshots>
 <url type="homepage">https://ricin.im</url>
 <update_contact>skyzohkey@protonmail.com</update_contact>
 <project_group>RicinApp</project_group>
</component>
